Champaign, Illinois Software Developer 217.402.4961| email

JEAN-PAUL WILSON



Python developer with 7 years experience in all phases of SDLC. Proficient at designing, building and deploying web applications (Flask, Django); building data pipelines and carrying out statistical and numerical analysis for operational improvement. Experienced project manager. Willing and excited to learn new tools & technologies.

Projects

Recently Built Django App

Site

2019

Ad-free news app where anyone can create an account and write news articles & get paid by subscribers.
 Can sign in as a user and subscribe to news channels for \$0.50/ channel/ month. Django app on Ubuntu instance and Apache2 Server, deployed to AWS EC2 with Lambda scripts for stripe payments.

Recently Built Flask App

Site | Repo

2018

 A web app where anyone can add lists of anything they want; OAuth2 to CUD; PostgreSQL; SQLAlchemy ORM with Flask framework; running on Ubuntu instance and Apache2 Server, deployed to AWS EC2.

Vehicle & Lane Detection via Dashcam

2017

Built a model that detects and tracks other vehicles from dashcam footage.
 Made use of OpenCV & other python libraries to detect lane lines in dashcam footage.
 Video | Notebook
 Video | Repo

Deep Learning (CNN) for self driving car

Video | Report & Repo

2017

Behavioral Cloning - Keras Model for self driving agent implemented in Unity.

Work History

Contractor, Python Developer

Champaign, IL (remote) | July 2017 - present

- Wrangling, processing, analysing & interpreting data from telemetry systems on Solar PV plant, building
 jupyter pipelines, ending w/ ML (img clsfr) & presentation (Tableau) to stakeholders.
- Developed business logic for new web application;
- Contribute to 'build, test and deploy' cycle in Agile team.

Eskom Holdings, Senior Analyst & Developer

Johannesburg | April 2014 – June 2017

- Built, deployed and maintained web apps (Flask) for research (solar, UCG (underground coal gasification), water treatment) departments; AWS deployment; Network and sysadmin functions: configuring (Ubuntu) VMs, servers, connecting to dbs, adding users, etc.
- Created REST API services for some of applications above.
- Mgmt & finance: Member of team completing business case for \$1bn Commercial Phase of UCG. Managed 8 mech, chem & elec engineers.

Eskom Holdings, Analyst & Developer

Johannesburg | March 2013 - March 2014

- Several data analysis projects using Python libs, improving operational costs & efficiency.
- Developed scripts to migrate data to PostgreSQL.
- Developed views and templates for Django application to allow for analysis and report creation.

Eskom Holdings, Mechanical Design Engineer

Johannesburg | January 2008 – February 2013

- Implemented drilling analysis program (forms in excel, VBA, later TkInter) saving ~20 man-hours/ day.
- Mech Eng: Design, construction, commissioning gas & water treatment plant. | Designed wellhead isolation system saving ~\$5m in operating equipment. | Redesigned condensate removal, reducing blockages by 30%. | Pipe stress analysis with CAESAR. Other eng software (SOLIDWORKS, CADWorx, Smartplant 3D).

Education

| Udacity Self Driving Car Engineer & Machine Learning Foundations Nanodegrees | 2018 |
|------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------|
| Udacity Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree | 2016 |
| University of the Witwatersrand, MSc Engineering (Mechanical) | 2014 |
| University of the Witwatersrand, BSc Engineering (Mechanical) | 2008 |

COMMUNITY: Mentor for 14 Udacity students, holding weekly Webinars, 1:1 coaching and Slack AMAs